To build up this list item we created a horizontal linear layout with three
children. The first child is an image view. The second child is a vertical
linear layout composed of two text views stacked on top of each other.
The third child is the same. It's a vertical linear layout composed of
the two temperature text views stacked on top of each other.
Now you might be wondering why we didn't use a relative layout.
Because that would give us less layers of hierarchy. Well, relative layouts
are good if you want to specify that one view should be to the right of another,
or on top of another view. Relative layouts are also good if you want a view to
be aligned to the parents left, top, right or bottom. But it's harder in this
case to center these two text views within the vertical height allocated by this
image view. It's easier with the linear layout here and here, so if the image
was any taller, these two text views would still stay vertically centered. And
this is what it looks like in the Device Preview within Android Studio.
I want to point out one thing about this horizontal linear layout,
which has three children. The image view, the vertical linear layout, and
the other vertical linear layout. The second child actually has a width of zero
DP but a weight of one. That means that any horizontal space that's not taken up
by other children will be distributed among views that have assigned weights. So
if we look at this third child, it has a width of wrap content and
a weight of zero. If we gave it a weight of one,
then it would stretch out like this. Basically the icon is a fixed width, and
then the remaining horizontal space is divided among these two children.
Since they both have a weight one, it's distributed equally. But if you look at
the wire frames, these temperature views are actually aligned to the right. So
all we need is for the width to be wrap content, and for the weight to be zero.
Then any remaining horizontal space will be assigned to this middle element,
with a weight of one. And this is the code for the xml layout.
We have a linear layout in horizontal orientation. The width is match parent to
match the width of the screen, and each list item has wrap content on its
height. But it does have a minimum height at least of this attribute,
list preferred item height. We specify gravity to be center vertical so that
all of its children are vertically centered within it. We also specify a little
bit of padding. Inside of it, we add an image view, which has wrap content for
height and width. And we specify the source as this placeholder drawable.
Next we have the vertical linear layout, where the width is zero DP and
the weight is one. We specify a little bit of padding between this view and
the icon beside it. Within the linear layout,
we have the date_textview as well as the forecast_textview. Beside that,
we have another vertical linear layout with the high temperature_textview and
the low temperature_textview. And that's it.